NAZMUL HOSSAIN

Address: Ahad Vila, Road-2, Lawai, South Surma, Sylhet, Bangladesh.

Contact: +8801675-870047 | Email: wall.mate@gmail.com | Skype: ataur.hussain

Github: https://github.com/hassantvs24

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/nazmul-hossain-456b83b2

OVERVIEW

I am a Full Stack Developer with more than 5 years of experience. I have Hands-on experience in client-side web development & server-side communication with RESTful web services. I have developed the architecture of university management systems, e-commerce, and e-business solutions. I know application deployment and life cycle maintenance processes. I have a full grasp in all aspects of object-oriented / database design and implementation. Furthermore, I have good knowledge of frontend development. Loves to create complex web applications with a rich user interface and broad set of skills applicable across different domains.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer (Remote) at Getonnet Norge

November 2020 - Present - Ringsevja 2, 3830 Ulefoss, Norway

Working here as a full stack developer and developing user-friendly applications with rich UI. Ongoing development and maintenance of new and existing projects. Plan and design project architecture for new applications or extend modules for existing projects, by maintaining the SOLID principles alongside. Also, manage team and write test case for unit testing.

Node.js | Laravel | Express.js | Rest API | React.js | TypeScript | MySQL | MongoDB | Git | GitHub

Software Engineer at Infinity Flame Soft

April 2016 – September 2020 - Bondor bazar, Sylhet, Bangladesh

When the company was newly formed, I joined here. Proud to be a part of the rise of this company. Most of the projects and websites were developed by me. I have built many complex web applications with rich UI.

Business solutions, I developed or contributed: POS System, Pharmacy Management, Business Accounting Solution, Payroll and Salary Management, Inventory Management, University Management System.

Laravel | Node.js | React.js | Vue.js | TypeScript | Rest API | MySQL | Git | GitHub

Software Developer at It Lab Solutions Ltd.

November 2014 – March 2016 - Jail Road, Sylhet, Bangladesh

I started as a front-end web & JavaScript developer. But for my good back-end skill, worked as a full-stack web developer. Here, I developed & contribute their most 3 successful products, School management, POS System & Hotel Management systems. Also, contributed to their blood donating app, I implement location wise user search system. Created RESTfull API for ridesharing mobile app.

Codelgniter | Laravel | jQuery | Responsive Design | Rest API | MySQL | Git | GitHub

EDUCATION

Leading University - Sylhet, Bangladesh

B.Sc. in Computer Science and Engineering - May 2011 - December 2019

SKILL & COMPETENCES

Programing Language: PHP | JavaScript

Framework: Laravel | Codelgniter | Express.js | Jest

Library: React.js | Vue.js | TypeScript | jQuery | Webpack | Babel | Gulp.js | Node.js

Database: MySQL | PostgreSQL | MongoDB

Front- End Development: HTML5 | CSS3 | SASS | SCSS

App Development: React Native

Version Control: Git | GitHub | Jenkins

Server: Nginx | Apache | Docker

CMS: WordPress

Unit Testing: I have good knowledge and experience on Test Driven Development (TDD)

SOLID Principles: I have hand on experience on single Responsibility principle, Open-closed principle, Liskov substitution principle, Interface segregation principle, and Dependency inversion principle

SOME PROJECTS

Sylheti Bazar

Laravel | Vue.js | Rest API | MySQL

This is a complete eCommerce solution.

Website: http://sylhetibazar.com

Cash Army

Laravel | Blade | Rest API | MySQL

This is a POS and Inventory System for Small & Medium businesses.

Website: http://army.sylhetibazar.com

LANGUAGE

English (Professional) | Bangla (Native)